<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on dumbfunded</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on dumbfunded</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 10:44:56 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Lytro forgets about all the little people</title>
      <link>/post/lytro-forgets-about-all-the-little-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 10:44:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/lytro-forgets-about-all-the-little-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dumbfunded.imgix.net/stroller.jpg?w=640&amp;amp;h=440&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;q=90&#34; alt=&#34;The Lytro Gilded Age&#34; title=&#34;Lytro! Camera! Action!&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lytro&lt;/strong&gt; (VC: $140mm) &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mirrorlessrumors.com/lytro-gives-up-his-photobusiness/&#34;&gt;threw in the towel&lt;/a&gt; right after raising a bunch more money. Not to
worry though! This isn&amp;rsquo;t the end for Lytro, they just aren&amp;rsquo;t going to make anything remotely like what their customers wanted to buy ever again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did they use to make?&lt;/strong&gt; Lytro gave the consumer camera market the old college try, producing two very different cameras years apart and throwing each
one into the Amazon Thunderdome to bleed and die alone. Each model served a different, oddly specific, likely non-existent niche with the only unifying Lytro
touches consisting of that light field crap and their penchant for bizarre form factors (seemingly intended to kick off a custom camera bag side business that
never materialized).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first Lytro camera, creatively named &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dpreview.com/articles/4755156977/lytrocameraannounced&#34;&gt;Light Field Camera&lt;/a&gt;, cost $400 and looked like a
short, squared spyglass. It came in a bunch of colors complementary to the average shoulder parrot and was apparently targeted at pirate captains &amp;ndash; a group
well-renowned for their early adoption of scurvy dogs and shivvered timbers. It&amp;rsquo;s unclear whether Lytro actually sold any of these cameras, or if their
shipments were all shanghaied off the coast of Somalia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the Light Field Camera failed to produce its anticipated booty, Lytro thought for a quick minute that maybe there was some reason why camera bodies are
all shaped similarly (hint: human hands), but you know what, that&amp;rsquo;s probably just coincidence. So they made the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dpreview.com/articles/5591433745/lytro-announces-illum-light-field-camera&#34;&gt;Lytro
Italic&lt;/a&gt;, the first SLR-ish camera with an oblique form factor. Oh and it
also has a non-interchangeable zoom lens just like all semi-pro cameras. This time around they decided to price it aspirationally at $1600, because damn that
light field stuff was hard work and someone is going to pay for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sales of this camera were &lt;a href=&#34;http://fortune.com/2014/11/06/camera-startup-lytro-makes-enterprise-gamble/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;awesome&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, apparently based on a scale that starts
out on the low end with &amp;ldquo;awesome&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;badass&amp;rdquo; and ends just past &amp;ldquo;wicked&amp;rdquo;, at &amp;ldquo;zoinks&amp;rdquo;. All the Leica cameras ever sold only gets them into the &amp;ldquo;cool, cool&amp;rdquo;
bracket, but every iPhone combined dominates the field at &amp;ldquo;yippee&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lytro planned future models to expand their lineup into bold, extra black extended oblique and bubble letter inspired camera shapes, but sadly it was not to
be. Since everyone was too busy not buying cameras from the likes of
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dpreview.com/articles/5928296460/canon-q4-earnings-report-shows-camera-sales-are-down&#34;&gt;Canon&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amateurphotographer.co.uk/latest/photo-news/nikon-is-latest-camera-maker-to-suffer-sales-drop-65540&#34;&gt;Nikon&lt;/a&gt;, they couldn&amp;rsquo;t be bothered to feel bad
about also not buying digital spyglasses and SLRs with factory seconds bodies from a no-name like Lytro. Faced with only &amp;ldquo;awesome&amp;rdquo; sales, Lytro had to give up
on their consumer camera dreams just four years in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who got canned?&lt;/strong&gt; 50 out of 130 employees got the boot, adjusting Lytro&amp;rsquo;s employee aperture from f/1.8 to f/4.0. The body count hopefully included whoever
thought spyglasses were poised to come back into style. It&amp;rsquo;s also very likely to include the people responsible for Lytro&amp;rsquo;s online services, so maybe get your
photos out of there before they all get taken on an incredible journey?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lytro also lost &lt;a href=&#34;http://recode.net/2014/11/25/lytro-chairman-to-take-post-as-berkeley-professor-in-2015/&#34;&gt;their founder&lt;/a&gt; a while back to the siren call of
academia and all of the associated money and fame of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eecs.berkeley.edu/Courses/Data/214.html&#34;&gt;teaching 100-level courses&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How screwed are customers?&lt;/strong&gt; Medium-screwed. Lytro cameras use a proprietary image format, and you need their desktop software to actually make their images
safe for human eyeballs. Lytro also promised a bunch of firmware updates, and it seems kind of unlikely any of that is happening now that they don&amp;rsquo;t love you
anymore. On the plus side, at least they aren&amp;rsquo;t pushing one last update to disable your shutter button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Did they fess up?&lt;/strong&gt; Kind of, but Lytro hasn&amp;rsquo;t come right out and said &amp;ldquo;we sold you dinosaurs right before a meteor strike.&amp;rdquo; It would seem by &lt;a href=&#34;https://backchannel.com/war-stories-why-i-lit-up-lytro-b46124da32a6&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;lit
up&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; their CEO is suggesting the situation with their consumer business is akin to
lighting your house on fire to evade friends and especially creditors, then leaving town to start a new life far, far away working at a Cinnabon in the
desperate hope that no one  comes looking for you. Kind of like how Lytro wants to move to Hollywood and sell movie cameras now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do they think is cool now?&lt;/strong&gt; Talking pictures, see? There&amp;rsquo;s no future in re-focusing photos of clippers to see if they&amp;rsquo;re sailing under the colors of
the Queen&amp;rsquo;s Navy. There&amp;rsquo;s money to be made in Hollywood and Lytro aims to get a piece of that pie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lytro wants to make a whole &lt;a href=&#34;https://lytro.com/cinema&#34;&gt;movie camera system&lt;/a&gt; now, and for once it looks like they intend to produce a camera in a suitable form
factor and pitch it at an audience that might care to purchase it. I&amp;rsquo;m sure it was extremely tempting to make a giant purple octopus shaped movie camera
without any physical buttons, using a Siri-style AI assistant that you yell &amp;ldquo;LYTRO! ACTION!&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;LYTRO! CUT! OH MY GOD I DIDN&amp;rsquo;T SAY WIPE DATA!&amp;rdquo; at, but Lytro
managed to show a little restraint around its new friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They also seem to think &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lytro.com/immerge&#34;&gt;VR&lt;/a&gt; is going to be a thing, but we all know that shit is a fad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Will it work?&lt;/strong&gt; They might have a shot. Removing backgrounds could be a minor revolution in film making, and the camera&amp;rsquo;s specs are way beyond what anyone
else has on the market today. Lytro has to prove themselves though, and the simple fact is that no studio is going to trust their $100 million movie to the
latest shiny toy to go cross-valley. Lytro is going to need that warchest to make it through the next few years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For comparison, it took Red nearly four years before the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0892255/&#34;&gt;first major picture&lt;/a&gt; was filmed with their first camera. It
was another two years before business really started to pick up in earnest. Every other company in the motion picture camera business was founded before 1950.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lytro needs to speak the language of Hollywood and hire people who know the industry if they want to succeed. Talking about how their camera is &lt;a href=&#34;http://techcrunch.com/2016/04/11/lytro-cinema-is-giving-filmmakers-400-gigabytes-per-second-of-creative-freedom/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;military
grade&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; and offering it only as a rental
aren&amp;rsquo;t necessarily recipes for success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What Lytro has really done with this pivot is to switch up the list of potential acquirers for their technology. Canon and Nikon are struggling to survive as
it is, they don&amp;rsquo;t have the money to splash around on a big acquisition of a VC-funded boondoggle. Maybe Arri or Paramount or somebody else in southern
California does?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yo</title>
      <link>/post/yo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 01:20:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/yo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dumbfunded.imgix.net/yo_screen.jpg?w=640&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;q=90&#34; alt=&#34;Yo This!&#34; title=&#34;Yo, you got Yo?&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yo&lt;/strong&gt; (VC: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/yo&#34;&gt;$1.5mm&lt;/a&gt;). Communication. Tersified. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yahoo.com/&#34;&gt;Purple&lt;/a&gt;. $750k / letter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Will investors make their money back?&lt;/strong&gt; Nuh&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Should you enjoy the free ride?&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;hellip;uh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who is this disrupting???&lt;/strong&gt; Snapchat?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investor Dumbness Quotient (IDQ)&lt;/strong&gt; A&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Obligatory Puff Piece (OPP)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ameliarianaa/status/718331550576865280&#34;&gt;Someone on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; still drops yo&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luxe and the more buxe</title>
      <link>/post/luxe-and-the-more-buxe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 12:04:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/luxe-and-the-more-buxe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dumbfunded.imgix.net/luxe_skater.jpg?w=640&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;q=90&#34; alt=&#34;Luxe Skater Boi&#34; title=&#34;This guy is totally thinking about doing a fakie ollie right into the 
driver&#39;s seat of that car&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fact:&lt;/strong&gt; it sucks to drive in The Big City. There are as many reasons for this suckage as there are drivers in this garbage can we call San Francisco (or
wherever you live, it&amp;rsquo;s probably the same), and each of them has at least two or three startups trying to burn VC money and be the first to go out of
business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reason #78: groceries and other junk shifting around in the trunk. You just know that was the bag with the eggs in it that fell over, damn it. Associated
startups: Instacart, Safeway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reason #32: motorcyclists popping wheelies while weaving between stopped cars. Associated startups: none out of stealth mode, opportunity is knocking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reason #4: Parking!! I hate you so much!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any number of startups have tried to crack city parking, going all the way back to the heady days of 2001 and the big boom of making cars go boom upon
request. There were companies that would put a brick on your accelerator pedal and gun it right into the bay (&lt;em&gt;no parking meters there&lt;/em&gt;). People stood around
outside of fancy restaurants with rags soaked in Dom Pérignon and Zippo lighters (&lt;em&gt;only the finest for your Maserati&amp;rsquo;s final fireball&lt;/em&gt;). One of the most
innovative companies of that time operated a chain of roaming chop shops that could part out a car in 5 minutes or less or it&amp;rsquo;s free (&lt;em&gt;take that Domino&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/em&gt;).
But repeat customers proved elusive, and simple mistakes like torching the right white Honda Civic on the wrong block could prove devasting. By 2002 it was
all over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it&amp;rsquo;s over a decade later, and &lt;strong&gt;Luxe&lt;/strong&gt; (neé Luxe Valet) &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/luxe-valet&#34;&gt;(VC $75.5mm)&lt;/a&gt; has a new take on this old
chestnut. They aren&amp;rsquo;t going to blow-, chop-, or in general fuck-up your ride &amp;ndash; they just want their loosely allied gang of skater punks to take your car to
an undisclosed location where people definitely will not have sex in it. Most crucially as compared to their predecessors-in-venture, Luxe will even bring
your car back provided that your Luxe Punk isn&amp;rsquo;t currently trying to pull off a wicked 540 kickflip, man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Will investors make their money back?&lt;/strong&gt; Besides the inherent risks of doing business in the volatile skater gang economy, Luxe also has a slight problem
when it comes to trying to undercut businesses whose costs consist solely of repainting the lines once every ten years whether they needs it or not. You
simply can&amp;rsquo;t park a car for what Luxe is charging in San Francisco, so unless they&amp;rsquo;re putting their VC money towards building a secret tunnel under the bay to
Treasure Island, they may have a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clearest path to profitability is for Luxe to secretly drive these &amp;ldquo;parked&amp;rdquo; cars for Uber and then pull a Ferris Bueller maneuver on that odometer before
returning them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Should you enjoy the free ride?&lt;/strong&gt; Uh, yeah. It&amp;rsquo;s VC-subsidized parking in cities where a dimly lit, predator-filled garage starts at $30 a day. Your car
re-appears when and where you want it, using the power of skater magic. Until you can buy a car that comes with a remote drone operator and Predator Parking
mode (&lt;em&gt;enabling your car to hunt for parking spaces and evade meter maids with military precision&lt;/em&gt;), this is the best thing going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who is this disrupting???&lt;/strong&gt; Those parking lot attendants who finagle your car into a space visibly smaller than it faster than you can manage a high pitched
&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;oh god wait&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;! They don&amp;rsquo;t even adjust the mirrors, it&amp;rsquo;s absurd. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t pull these moves off with a team of five people in an hour going an inch at a
time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, are you supposed to tip? Coming and going, or just when you pick your car up?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investor Dumbness Quotient (IDQ)&lt;/strong&gt; Certified IDQ rating F. Pretty smart really, as long as they&amp;rsquo;re investing other people&amp;rsquo;s money. These investors get free
valet parking everywhere they go for a few years, so why not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Obligatory puff piece (OPP)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessinsider.com/hertz-invests-in-luxe-valet-parking-2016-4&#34;&gt;Business Insider&lt;/a&gt; is very excited to regurgitate
exactly what Luxe told them about being pretty much almost profitable if you just look at their Excel sheet from this one particular spot in only this room.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revolv Shutdown</title>
      <link>/post/revolv-shutdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 03:56:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/revolv-shutdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dumbfunded.imgix.net/revolv.jpg?w=640&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;q=90&#34; alt=&#34;Revolv in happier times&#34; title=&#34;The Revolv family in happier times. No one could have predicted they would all be dead within two years.&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revolv&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/revolv&#34;&gt;(VC: $7.3mm)&lt;/a&gt; made a dingus to smarten up your home. I guess it turned your lights on when you
told it to with your phone, but nobody is really sure. Nest bought them back in October 2014 and discontinued said dingus with a quickness, but kept its cloud
service running. As of May 15 2016 the free ride is over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why is this happening?&lt;/strong&gt; First of all, &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20150609233637/https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.revolv.android.app&amp;amp;hl=en&#34;&gt;no
one&lt;/a&gt; bought this thing. It also hasn&amp;rsquo;t
been sold in 18 months and Nest clearly viewed it as an evolutionary dead end. The fact that Revolv was acqui-shutdowned by Nest pretty much says everything
there is to say about the success of their product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How much notice?&lt;/strong&gt; 45 days. I mean, it&amp;rsquo;s just the thing that (hypothetically) controls your entire house so that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a big deal right? Nest is
trying to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessinsider.com/whats-going-on-at-nest-2016-2&#34;&gt;get sold&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://recode.net/2016/03/30/nest-2015-sales-budget/&#34;&gt;shutdown&lt;/a&gt;
themselves you know, they don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vox.com/2016/4/7/11378904/nest-tony-fadell-struggling&#34;&gt;have all day&lt;/a&gt; for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How screwed are customers?&lt;/strong&gt; If someone bought said dingus (which included a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessinsider.com/revolv-smart-home-hubs-lifetime-subscription-bricked-nest-google-alphabet-internet-of-things-2016-4&#34;&gt;lifetime
subscription&lt;/a&gt;, where by
lifetime they actually meant the length of time a Nest product manager&amp;rsquo;s political capital could be drained to sustain the service) right before it was pulled
from shelves, they wound up paying $17 per month for it. For just the price of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fastfoodmenuprices.com/starbucks-prices/&#34;&gt;9 cups of coffee&lt;/a&gt; each
month, this ugly red tupperware container / irregular tortilla holder was yours to keep. And once it&amp;rsquo;s useful Internet-of-Dumb-Things lifespan is over, it has
a long second life ahead of it as a paperweight or cautionary reminder of the fickleness of The Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do people feel about it?&lt;/strong&gt; Pretty safe to say &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@arlogilbert/the-time-that-tony-fadell-sold-me-a-container-of-hummus-cb0941c762c1&#34;&gt;people
care&lt;/a&gt; more about the death of Revolv than they ever
cared about it during its life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Was the phrase &amp;lsquo;Incredible Journey&amp;rsquo; used?&lt;/strong&gt; No, but &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.revolv.com/&#34;&gt;the sentiment&lt;/a&gt; is clearly there. The thing you liked &amp;ldquo;wasn&amp;rsquo;t perfect&amp;rdquo;, the team
has gone on to make something &amp;ldquo;flat-out better&amp;rdquo;, and most importantly shutting down is only &amp;ldquo;the beginning&amp;rdquo;. The beginning, perhaps, of a new and even more
incredible journey?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kuveé</title>
      <link>/post/kuvee/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/kuvee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dumbfunded.imgix.net/kuvee.jpg?w=640&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;q=90&#34; alt=&#34;The ecstacy of Kuvee&#34; title=&#34;What do you mean, your wine bottle is incompatible with my Merlot?&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you ever wish that drinking adult grape juice could involve more pretentiousness and gadgetry? &lt;strong&gt;Kuveé&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/kuvee&#34;&gt;(VC:
$6mm)&lt;/a&gt; sure as shit did. Their smart wine bottle brings the exciting technological world of vendor lock-in,
cloud services that will soon be shut down and miniscule battery life to the staid world of smushed grapes in bottles. You can tell that they mean business,
because they figured out how to put an accent mark on one of their &lt;em&gt;e&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One suspects that the wine bottle connects to The Cloud simply because someone had a bunch of leftover AWS credits and this was the best idea anyone could
come up with to burn them off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Will investors make their money back?&lt;/strong&gt; Seems real unlikely, but people do seem to drink a lot of this stuff already. They need to sell like 2 million
bottles of wine to recoup the investment to date, and it&amp;rsquo;s not like anything could possibly go wrong before that happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Should you enjoy the free ride?&lt;/strong&gt; The wine isn&amp;rsquo;t particularly any cheaper than down the street, but it does come in fancy bottles with screw tops and you
can buy it in the middle of the night (not unlike buying a ticket to board the Night Train). No word yet on whether Kuveé&amp;rsquo;s Smart Bottle works with third-party paper bag accessories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of investing in a Wine Consumption System, you could just drink your wine faster. Or buy smaller bottles. If you are really determined to be a nerd
about it, just &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coravin.com/&#34;&gt;inject some argon&lt;/a&gt; in there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who is this disrupting???&lt;/strong&gt; Kuveé is working with partner vineyards, so it isn&amp;rsquo;t the entire wine industry. Not really the wine bottle industry either. Hmm.
Is it those fat cats in the wine cork industry?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investor Dumbness Quotient (IDQ)&lt;/strong&gt; Certified IDQ rating B. A robo wine bottle is dumb. Kuveé&amp;rsquo;s Smart Bottle design doesn&amp;rsquo;t even do much for freshness
beyond hopeful optimism. Kuveé is also adding another layer of middlemanery to an industry literally bursting at the seams with mid-men. Who knows though,
maybe they&amp;rsquo;ll only lose half of their money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Obligatory puff piece (OPP)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wired.com/2016/03/kuvee-wine-bottle/&#34;&gt;Wired&lt;/a&gt; seems real excited about getting some fancy screw-top wine for the
office.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soylent &#43; Vessyl</title>
      <link>/post/soylent-vessyl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 04:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/soylent-vessyl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dumbfunded.imgix.net/soylent_vessyl_logo.png?w=640&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;q=90&#34; alt=&#34;Vessoyl&#34; title=&#34;Warranty void if anything that tastes pleasant enters drinking unit&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soylent&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/soylent-corporation&#34;&gt;(VC: $22.3mm)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Vessyl&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/mark-one&#34;&gt;(VC:
$3mm)&lt;/a&gt; are two titans of the Liquids-as-a-Service economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These companies are also bitter rivals with polar opposite views on matter caught between the gaseous and solid phases. Soylent militantly opposes any &lt;a href=&#34;http://robrhinehart.com/?p=298&#34;&gt;human
consumption&lt;/a&gt; of a liquid other than its extremely viscous namesake. Vessyl promises to reveal the inner lives of all liquids to you, can you just give us a little longer? Can these mortal enemies make nice?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To recap: Vessyl still hasn&amp;rsquo;t shipped the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.myvessyl.com/vessyl/&#34;&gt;most awesome cup ever&lt;/a&gt;, originally scheduled for Q1 2015. They probably never
will for a variety of reasons, most notably that the product is painfully stupid and totally pointless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It isn&amp;rsquo;t just the laws of chemistry and physics that prevent Vessyl from forging their Holy Grayl. There&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a math problem too. By now they&amp;rsquo;ve
learned that $3 million just isn&amp;rsquo;t enough money to bring their groundbreaking vision of the Internet of Cups (IoC) to life. Most of that cash has been spent trying to get people to accidentally put a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.myvessyl.com/prymevessyl/&#34;&gt;water-only Vessyl&lt;/a&gt; into their &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Mark-One-Vessyl-Pryme/dp/B019CN5M4Y/&#34;&gt;Amazon shopping cart&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; in the hopes that someone out there won&amp;rsquo;t mind buying a cup that costs as much as every other cup they will ever buy because it tells you that the water you just poured in it is still in fact there and also please charge my battery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flailing around in their desperation, Vessyl has also come upon their salvation. They have climbed Mount Olympus and stolen the secret of water from the
gods. They have created a single-liquid Vessyl, and what better pairing for it than the only VC-backed liquid capable of supporting human life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Introducing &lt;strong&gt;Vessyl: Just Soylent&lt;/strong&gt;. All of the thick, sludgelike goodness you&amp;rsquo;ve come to expect from Soylent working in perfect harmony with the high tech
beep-booping of Vessyl&amp;rsquo;s industry first $200 smart cup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The possibilities are endless:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remind you that you&amp;rsquo;re running low on Soylent (&lt;em&gt;orders must be received at least 6 months in advance&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cross-reference the Soylent in your Vessyl with the Soylent Changelog and link you to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://files.soylent.com/pdf/soylent-release-notes-1-4.pdf&#34;&gt;release
notes&lt;/a&gt; for your branch&amp;rsquo;s latest commit hash.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Offer helpful tips for food that pairs well with the rich, gag-reflex triggering goodness of Soylent (dirt, tree bark, small to medium insects).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best of all, with &lt;strong&gt;Vessyl: Just Soylent&lt;/strong&gt;, there&amp;rsquo;s no need for them to actually do that thing they said they were going to do that sounded kind of hard.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Juicero: You Juice Bro?</title>
      <link>/post/juicero-you-juice-bro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 03:24:25 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/juicero-you-juice-bro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dumbfunded.imgix.net/juicero_image.png?w=640&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;q=90&#34; alt=&#34;The Majestic Juicebro&#34; title=&#34;Packet opacity is a key design choice. Seeing the disgusting 
inner workings will result in temporary or permanent insanity.&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This thing slices, quite possibly dices. It also squeezes a pre-filled packet so hard that goop you drink falls out. Prototypes exploded. In this economy
that equals big VC money for &lt;strong&gt;Juicero&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/juicero&#34;&gt;(VC: $120mm)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Will investors make their money back?&lt;/strong&gt; Not a chance, these guys blended and drank it all already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Should you enjoy the free ride?&lt;/strong&gt; At $700 plus juice rental fees, the Juicebro is not exactly a VC-funded steal. Maybe you should stick to the tried and
true method of obtaining cheap juice? For the record, that’s: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get Instacart to bring a bag of fruit or whatever to your place, leave it in the street.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have a Lyft driver back over the bag a few times.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally a Handy-person comes by to “clean up” the mess and leaves it for you in a jug in the fridge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who is this disrupting???&lt;/strong&gt; That guy at the farmer&amp;rsquo;s market clinging to a subsistence level income, who already has Odwalla nipping at his heels. Big
Bottled Juice of course is feeling the burn from some random juice bar down the street (only available in cities with considerable hipster or hippie enclaves).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investor Dumbness Quotient (IDQ)&lt;/strong&gt; Certified IDQ rating B. Pretty dumb, but someone might actually buy a few of them at least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Obligatory Puff Piece (OPP)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vogue.com/13421774/juicero-cold-pressed-juice-home-juicer-no-mess/&#34;&gt;Vogue&lt;/a&gt; is ready for some juice now please!
Includes bonus photo of random juice-holding model from the year 6 BJ (Before Juicebro).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>