<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Juicero on dumbfunded</title>
    <link>/tags/juicero/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Juicero on dumbfunded</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 03:24:25 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/juicero/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Juicero: You Juice Bro?</title>
      <link>/post/juicero-you-juice-bro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 03:24:25 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/juicero-you-juice-bro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dumbfunded.imgix.net/juicero_image.png?w=640&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;q=90&#34; alt=&#34;The Majestic Juicebro&#34; title=&#34;Packet opacity is a key design choice. Seeing the disgusting 
inner workings will result in temporary or permanent insanity.&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This thing slices, quite possibly dices. It also squeezes a pre-filled packet so hard that goop you drink falls out. Prototypes exploded. In this economy
that equals big VC money for &lt;strong&gt;Juicero&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/juicero&#34;&gt;(VC: $120mm)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Will investors make their money back?&lt;/strong&gt; Not a chance, these guys blended and drank it all already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Should you enjoy the free ride?&lt;/strong&gt; At $700 plus juice rental fees, the Juicebro is not exactly a VC-funded steal. Maybe you should stick to the tried and
true method of obtaining cheap juice? For the record, that’s: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get Instacart to bring a bag of fruit or whatever to your place, leave it in the street.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have a Lyft driver back over the bag a few times.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally a Handy-person comes by to “clean up” the mess and leaves it for you in a jug in the fridge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who is this disrupting???&lt;/strong&gt; That guy at the farmer&amp;rsquo;s market clinging to a subsistence level income, who already has Odwalla nipping at his heels. Big
Bottled Juice of course is feeling the burn from some random juice bar down the street (only available in cities with considerable hipster or hippie enclaves).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investor Dumbness Quotient (IDQ)&lt;/strong&gt; Certified IDQ rating B. Pretty dumb, but someone might actually buy a few of them at least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Obligatory Puff Piece (OPP)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vogue.com/13421774/juicero-cold-pressed-juice-home-juicer-no-mess/&#34;&gt;Vogue&lt;/a&gt; is ready for some juice now please!
Includes bonus photo of random juice-holding model from the year 6 BJ (Before Juicebro).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>